# ANAND AGGARWAL

# 2<sup>nd</sup> Year MChem with Industrial Placement Student

Email: agsa21@bath.ac.uk

Phone: 07769 710298

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/anand-aggarwal12/

Address: Rowacres, Bath, BA2 2LH

Teddington, TW11 8DX

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a self-motivated student with a strong interest in coding and data analysis, participating in various coding competitions for the past 8 years and completing numerous data courses. My experience in project management and data analytics spans many years. As a result, I already have a strong understanding of different roles within an organisation and the skills required to communicate effectively across teams.

I enjoy playing & watching sports such as football and tennis in my free time. I am a big mini-golf player and look to play as much as possible and I also try to visit/volunteer at the theatre when I get the chance.

#### **EDUCATION**

2020 - present **MChem Chemistry with Industrial Placement** 

University of Bath

Finished 1st Year with 68% average (2:1)

1st Year Units:	Grade:	2 <sup>nd</sup> Year Units:	Grade:
The chemistry of everyday things	75%		
General practical chemistry	71%		
From molecules to materials	68%		
Foundation chemistry laboratory	63%		
Fundamentals of organic chemistry	60%		
Atomic structure, bonding, and the Periodic Table	68%		
Introduction to environmental and sustainable chemistry	74%		
Kingston Grammar School			

#### 2013 - 2020K

A Levels in Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths and EPQ - A\*, A\*, A\*, A, A\* GCSEs - 6 A\*, 3 A, B

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### ROLE COMPANY

DATES

#### **Data Analyst Association of Corporate Treasurers July 2021**

Reviewed customer journeys and behaviours when students registered for and completed units/ passed exams. Examined whether there were any trends in a sample and, once presented to management, I expanded my analysis to the full dataset. The analysis was used by the finance team to produce more accurate forecasts and by the qualifications team to target which units require more support for students.

#### Academic Tutor Manning's Tutors

#### November 2020 – Present

As a tutor within the National Tutoring Programme (NTP), I work with disengaged and disadvantaged students in Maths and Science to catch up on lost learning due to the pandemic. With tuition only provided online, I had to be imaginative in ways to captivate students and flexible to each students learning style.

## Head of IT Cash, Currency & Payments Ltd

## September 2017 – Present

I worked on developing an easy to implement PowerBI dashboard that consultants could use. This enabled consultants not only to save time by having clear visual reports in real time, but also created a more efficient and on-demand service for the client.

## Director Anand's Tech Support

# **April 2019 – January 2021**

I created online profiles for small, local companies and enabled them to capture online business through bespoke websites, inventory management systems, and payment systems. This allowed businesses to respond to the pandemic quickly and profitably.

#### **SKILLS**

SKILL	DESCRIPTION	EVIDENCE
Coding	Proficient in <b>HTML</b> , <b>CSS</b> , <b>SQL</b> & <b>Python</b> . Adept at designing/developing databases and data analysis.	Winner of Young Rewired State Most Innovative Design 2014. Internship at the ACT.
Data Analysis	Adept at <b>cleaning</b> and <b>identifying trends</b> within sample sets. Experienced at extending to large data sets and writing up observations and recommendations.	Certificates: Microsoft Azure AI AI-900 ☐ Microsoft Azure Data DP-900 ☐ Internship at the ACT
Data Presentation	Collation of UX and consumer behaviour for businesses to tailor online experiences using Google Analytics. <b>Presentation of complex</b> <b>data sets</b> in an accessible report for management to take decisions.	Using skills acquired from Azure & Tableau courses to identify trends in datasets. Presented to management using <b>PowerBI.</b>
Project Management	Exceptional time management skills. Experienced at managing a team under high pressure situations and achieving goals for key stakeholders.	<b>Stage Manager</b> for 6 productions, including at <b>the Edinburgh Fringe Festival</b> 2019. Director of successful web design business.
Coaching	Private Tutor for over three years, building a great rapport with students. Achieved measured success, increasing attainment by 35%.	Qualification for Tutors CPD; Qualified Tutor

# REFERENCES

Dr. Barrie Marsh

Director of Studies

Department of Chemistry

University of Bath

bm250@bath.ac.uk

Steven Miles

Business Data Analyst

Association of Corporate Treasurers

London

smiles@treasurers.org